Raj Praveen S

Software Engineer @ Facebook

Summary

Graduate Student at Purdue University with 2.5 years of experience building applications in Java, C++ and Android. Oracle Certified Java Programmer and an active competitive programmer with good problem solving skills. Ranked 27th among competitive programmers in USA on Codechef.

Experience

Software Engineer at Facebook

January 2016 - Present

Graduate Assistant at Purdue University

June 2014 - Present

- Built a Web Log Viewer Application for the websites logs on all web servers hosted at Purdue.(PHP)
- Implemented features like merged log file view for a website hosted on multiple servers and pagination.
- Built automation scripts for setting up new websites on LAMP.

Software Engineer Intern at Facebook

June 2015 - August 2015 (3 months)

Developed new adinterfaces on Android

Web Developer at Office of Indiana State Chemist at Purdue University

January 2014 - June 2014 (6 months)

• Developed a PHP and JQuery based framework to create dynamic forms and Maps for a Web Application.

Software Engineer at KLA-Tencor

May 2013 - December 2013 (8 months)

• Optimized an API that queries and categorizes wafer defect attributes, improving running time by 75%.(C++)

Software Enginner at Lister Technologies

July 2011 - April 2013 (1 year 10 months)

- Extensive experience with Apex Classes, Test Methods, Web Services, Visual Force Pages, Visualforce components, Visualforce controllers and Apex Triggers on many projects.
- Developed an email-blasting app for Experian-Cheetahmail on Salesforce CRM for email marketing, the app triggered bulk emails, schedule emails and also tracked email stats using cheetahmail API.(Java, APEX)
- Developed an Android application that queries Product details from Salesforce based on QR Code.

Education

Purdue University

Master's Degree, Computer and Information Technology, 2014 - 2015

Shanmugha Arts, Science, Technology and Research Academy

B.Tech (Hons), Information Technology, Computer Science, 2007 - 2011

Activities and Societies: SCANIT

Honors and Awards

Deans List Scholarship, Department 1st in "Programming in C" course, Department 1st in the University Examinations,5th semester.

Raj Praveen S

Software Engineer @ Facebook



Contact Raj Praveen on LinkedIn